In this final video, we're just
going to discuss the benefits of
testing productivity and efficiency.
Now, as we've worked through the
course, there's been various parts
where I've used templates and there's
been guidelines, which I've been
able to follow,  shortcut keys.
And in one of the videos have
demonstrated how to create a macro.
And one of the things you need to do
is if you're working in an environment
where you need to ensure that you're
being efficient in your work and
you're not spending too much time.
So anything that is going to
improve productivity and efficiency,
or it's going to speed up the
processes, it's going to save money.
Because the more time you spend
on a product or the more time you
spend on an activity that is taking
time and time costs money, you
need to think about these things.
So for example, in the word processing
unit, we used the newsletter, which would
then be saved as a template, which could
then be filled in at a later date – so
the next month's or the next month's.
So you could use that as a basis, which
again, you would need to look at it and
say well will that improve productivity?
Well yes, it would
because you've created it.
And now all you need to do is edit
it to change it on a monthly basis.
Creating macros will improve productivity
because it'll automate a specific process
within a spreadsheet or a Word document.
So it takes away one of the mundane
tasks, so if you want something to
be applied to a specific selection of
text, or you want text to be displayed
in a certain way, or formulas to be
calculated automatically by using a
shortcut key, using the customising
menus and toolbars, which again, can
improve productivity and efficiency.
But again, you've got to look
at these and test them and
see whether they actually do.
And there may be instances where shortcut
keys do speed up the process, but again,
sometimes, as it can be just as quick
to click on the specific tool within
the program, but there's a wide range.
You can also assign new shortcuts
and create new shortcuts.
And just to give an example there, you
can look on your, File on spreadsheet, go
to your Options and in there you can...
the quick access toolbar, and you
can see all of the various commands.
So you could select cut, add
these to the quick access toolbar.
So if I selected the Create a Chart and
added that to  quick access toolbar,
again, you can see here along the toolbar
there I've now got Create Chart, so I
can go back in and select other options.
And again, I can customise the ribbon
to show a variety of different things.
The developer tab we
discussed in word processing.
Again, one of the things there is
it's more about how quickly it can
allow you to complete a task, as well
as using within software it's also
good that you could access feedback.
So if you present and create a document
and you can ask for feedback on that.
Working with other people that can
assist you because they may know
a quicker way of doing something.
And again, all of these things are
designed and developed to improve
the productivity and efficiency.
So the quicker you are and the more
efficient you are, the less time things
take and the less money things cost.
So it's always good to
test out new solutions.
And if you find that you have
an idea that you can utilize,
it's worth testing it out.
And then compare before and after, and you
will then see whether it was efficient.
If not just then you can
just go back to the old way.
But if it is, it means that
you've got a solution to specific
problems that you may encounter.